Hema Narayana Reddy

2658 Menlo Ave, Los Angeles, CA 90007 | (213) 298-0197

Email: hemanara@usc.edu LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hemanara Web: https://www-scf.usc.edu/~hemanara

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A skilled software developer with 3 years of industry experience on Java API development and leading-edge technologies. Seeking a summer internship as a software/web developer with a keen interest in web/mobile application development and user experience design.

EDUCATION

M.S., Computer Science

Aug 2015 - May 2017 (Expected)

University of Southern California (USC), Los Angeles

Courses: Analysis of Algorithms, Web Technologies, Advanced Mobile Devices and Game Consoles, Multimedia Systems Design

B.E. Information Science and Engineering | GPA: 3.7

Sep 2008 - Jun 2012

Vemana Institute of Technology (VIT), Bangalore

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ Programming Languages: Java, Core Java, C, C++
- ✓ <u>Databases/DBMS:</u> DB2, HQL, SQL, Oracle 10g, SQL Yog, MySQL, SQL Lite
- ✓ Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, XML, jQuery, php, Web Services (SOAP)
- ✓ Operating Systems: Android, Windows XP/Vista, UNIX, Linux
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, jQuery, MVC, OUAF (Oracle Utilities Application Framework with hibernate), JSF
- ✓ <u>Development Tools</u>: Oracle CC&B, Eclipse, Rational Software Architect, Rational Clear Case Remote Client, SQL Developer, SVN, FileZilla, Putty

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer & Application Developer, Java | IBM India Pvt. Ltd. Package Solution Consultant, Oracle Customer Care and Billing | IBM India

Sep 2012-Jun 2015

Jan 2014 - Jun 2015

- Implemented and Integrated services using OUAF for ALLETE, energy & utilities service provider in Minnesota, USA.
- Conducted Gap Analysis Workshops for the ALLETE requirement and developed Baseline Configuration in Phase I. Re-projected Costs of Deployment, Phase II with a not-to-exceed gap. Developed high complexity interfaces like batch programs, business components & algorithms.
- Optimized response times of batch job programs running on Linux client servers by 10%, by using HQL queries instead of SQL.
- Tuned Java methods that are called repeatedly by the business components and improved the performance by 15% during integration testing.
- Collaborated with IBM offshore and onshore team to fix high priority defects during IBM smoke testing & UAT that facilitated the IBM Go-Live.
- Volunteered to help CC&B practitioners in Java programming and mentored two IBM resources with java related queries.
- Felicitated with "Manager's choice award-2014" by Project Manager & Oracle Utility practice area lead for admirable performance at work.

Application developer, Java & J2EE | IBM India

Sep 2012 - Dec 2013

- Enhanced UI/UX to HTML 5 compliance in OrderMax, order capture and management application for Bell customer service, Canada.
- Developed Java programs in RSA to implement promotional code offers for Bell bundle products & carried out functional testing on SOAP UI.
- Held crucial responsibility in packaging & deploying the code to Bell clients in time. Took ownership to represent dev team during client calls.
- Resolved deployment and build issues on the Bell VMs during build failures in UAT & that helped IBM to maintain strong client relationships.
- Ownership of Billing, Order Summary and Additional Customer Information Pages Development for OrderMax application.
- Expertise in Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC) used in Waterfall and Agile methodologies. Actively involved in every phase from requirement gathering till production deployment.

ACADEMIC PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Android Weather Forecast App

Nov 2015

- Designed and implemented an android application that allows the user to perform weather forecast and post details on Facebook. The application displays weather data for the current day, next 24 hours and next 7 days. Utilized AERIS Android SDK to implement the maps.
- The application uses Apache web server and runs on AWS that queries RESTful web service providers like Google and Forecast.io APIs.

Weather Forecast Web App using Bootstrap, JQuery and Facebook Mashup

Oct 2015

Developed a web application using HTML, AJAX, JSON, PHP and Amazon cloud computing(AWS) server. Enhanced the UX with Bootstrap &
JQuery UI. The application provides an interface to perform the Weather forecast and post details to Facebook using Facebook Platform API.

Server Side Scripting in PHP

Oct 2015

• Created web page that allows users to search current weather information. The application uses Google geo code and Forecast.io APIs that take longitude and latitude of the current location to fetch the weather data. The weather information is displayed in the tabular format.

XML Parsing and Extraction of XML data

Sep 2015

• Developed HTML & JavaScript program that takes the URL of an XML document, parses the XML, extracts XML response & displays the data.

A Passenger's Buddy on Android | Android and Heroku Cloud Based Grails Mobile application

Jan 2012

- Developed an Android application with a specific goal to ensure safety and security of passengers, predominantly for women. The application interfaces with Heroku cloud-based Grails Server and includes features such as distance and fare calculation, location tracking and navigation.
- Won 'Best Android Project' award for the idea and implementation in the Mobile app category by the Department of Information Science, VIT.